<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>General on Casual Inference</title>
    <link>/categories/general/</link>
    <description>Recent content in General on Casual Inference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/general/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian birders</title>
      <link>/2021/06/07/bayesian-birders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/06/07/bayesian-birders/</guid>
      <description>After spending too much time in front of screens for most of 2020, I’ve tried to make space for more screenless activities that are pandemic-compatible. Evelyn and I got into birding late last year, and have been doing it pretty actively for most of 2021. We’ve been keeping track of our birding adventures on Instagram @OurBigYear.1 Besides the physical and mental health benefits of birding, it’s also an activity that suits data scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projections for the 2020 census</title>
      <link>/2020/09/27/projections-for-the-2020-census/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/27/projections-for-the-2020-census/</guid>
      <description>More of my work on Census 2020 got mentioned in the Washington Post! The article is about how the current wildfires and hurricanes affecting some states will affect the ability of enumerators to carry out non-response follow-up (NRFU). This compounds the threat imposed by the Trump administration cutting short the window for NRFU. The window is supposed to end September 30 (but there is a lawsuit going back-and-forth in the courts).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coronavirus and the 2020 census</title>
      <link>/2020/09/16/coronavirus-and-the-2020-census/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/09/16/coronavirus-and-the-2020-census/</guid>
      <description>It’s been awhile since I posted anything, which has been due to my being stretched thin at my job (on top of trying to survive a pandemic). In my work at Civis Analytics, I’ve been monitoring the progress of the census, which determines how federal funding and congressional seats are apportioned to the different states.
In the best of times, the census is a challenging logistical operation to execute well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to interpret statistical models</title>
      <link>/2020/06/08/how-to-interpret-statistical-models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/08/how-to-interpret-statistical-models/</guid>
      <description>In my work as a data scientist at Civis Analytics, I often have to explain the nuances of statistical models to clients without technical backgrounds.
With the recent Covid-19 pandemic, there has been a proliferation of epidemiological data and models being discussed online. Since public sector agencies need to make sense of these models, I wrote a short explainer (published by CivStart) for public sector officials on how to interpret Covid-19 models they might read about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello (again) world</title>
      <link>/2019/04/01/hello-again-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/01/hello-again-world/</guid>
      <description>For the last few months, I’ve been working almost exclusively on my dissertation and other academic research. Great news: I graduated! In July, I’ll be starting a position as a Data Scientist at Civis Analytics.
I figured it was time to get back into the habit of writing about side-projects, which would also give me the opportunity to learn and practice new computational methods. I intend to use this blog as a journal to keep track of cool things I’m learning (both methods and insights from the data I analyze).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>