<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Outdoors on Casual Inference</title>
    <link>/tags/outdoors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Outdoors on Casual Inference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/outdoors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian birders</title>
      <link>/2021/06/07/bayesian-birders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2021/06/07/bayesian-birders/</guid>
      <description>After spending too much time in front of screens for most of 2020, I’ve tried to make space for more screenless activities that were pandemic-compatible. Evelyn and I got into birding late last year, and have been doing it pretty actively for most of 2021. We’ve been keeping track of our birding adventures on Instagram @OurBigYear.1 Besides the physical and mental health benefits of birding, it’s also an activity that suits data scientists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing the (climbing) grade</title>
      <link>/2019/05/27/passing-the-climbing-grade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/27/passing-the-climbing-grade/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend, I had the chance to climb at the New River Gorge, one of the best climbing destinations on the East coast (and probably the closest world-class crag to where I live). Unfortunately, I’m rehabbing a wrist injury, so the hardest climb I got on was graded 5.9, several notches below the level I’m trying to climb at consistently. Fortunately, it was the classic epic 80-foot Flight of the Gumby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Park trails</title>
      <link>/2018/06/26/national-park-trails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/06/26/national-park-trails/</guid>
      <description>I love exploring the National Parks. Different parks contain different collections of hikes. I typically choose which park to visit based on a combination of sights I want to see and logistical constraints (e.g., travel time, cost, availability of campsites).
Once I’ve chosen a park to visit, I choose a set of trails to hike based on how much time/fitness I have (choosing hikes with distance and elevation gain within a certain range), with the goal of fitting in as many hikes as possible during my stay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Park visits</title>
      <link>/2017/06/30/national-park-visits/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/30/national-park-visits/</guid>
      <description>Last year, the National Park Service celebrated its 100th anniversary. I’ve had the privilege to camp at several of them in the last few years (you can see photos I’ve taken on some of my travels here), and I’ll be going to Rocky Mountain National Park in Colorado this Summer.
Growing popularity I think the National Parks are the greatest thing America has to offer. It seems many people agree – visitation has never been higher.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>