<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pop Culture on Casual Inference</title>
    <link>/tags/pop-culture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pop Culture on Casual Inference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/pop-culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting The Office: A text analysis</title>
      <link>/2020/02/05/revisiting-the-office-a-text-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/02/05/revisiting-the-office-a-text-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I’m casually rewatching The Office as my I need something uninvolved to half-occupy my brain for 20 minutes show. Its been almost seven years since the last episode aired, but I still quote it with my closest friends and family – such was its personal and cultural significance. It’s aged like high school: I look back with fondness at the familiar jokes, but there’s also a sense that it was a time we have outgrown.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing board games</title>
      <link>/2019/05/08/choosing-board-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/08/choosing-board-games/</guid>
      <description>Board games have been a significant part of my life. Many of my closest friendships were forged through repeated gaming sessions. With my friends from high-school, I progressed from simple gateway games like Munchkin to more complex ones like Power Grid. I’m certainly not alone as a passenger on the board game train.
What makes a good game, and relatedly, what should I play next? BoardGameGeek (BGG) is an online community that helps answer that question with reviews and discussions of almost anything that qualifies as a board/card game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Avengers popularity contest</title>
      <link>/2019/04/25/avengers-popularity-contest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/04/25/avengers-popularity-contest/</guid>
      <description>I’m catching Avengers: Endgame later today, early enough that I don’t have to hide from spoilers. The closing of this phase of the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU) completes the current storylines, but really the movies will continue unabated as long as Disney makes money off of them.
The Avengers, seen here powered by the Money Stone.
As someone who grew up following the Avengers in comic books, and then seeing them come to life on the screen, the ending of this phase is also emotionally significant.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>