<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sports on Casual Inference</title>
    <link>/tags/sports/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sports on Casual Inference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fantasy vs. reality: NFL player fantasy value in the 2019 season</title>
      <link>/2019/09/06/fantasy-vs-reality-nfl-player-fantasy-value-in-the-2019-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/09/06/fantasy-vs-reality-nfl-player-fantasy-value-in-the-2019-season/</guid>
      <description>Since writing my post analyzing real-world NFL player value, I’ve been waiting for a couple of Fantasy Football leagues I’m in to complete drafting before posting about fantasy value. (Wouldn’t want my opponents to think I’m putting more thought into my team than I actually am.)
In that post, I visualized player value – roughly, the ratio of each player’s Defense-adjusted Yards Above Replacement (DYAR) to their cap hit – for the 2018 season.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real world: NFL player value in the 2018 season</title>
      <link>/2019/08/19/real-world-nfl-player-value-in-the-2018-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/08/19/real-world-nfl-player-value-in-the-2018-season/</guid>
      <description>I learned to love American football through Fantasy Football, which I imagine is a pretty common gateway (especially for those with a quantitative bent). However, watching football through the lens of fantasy sports can distort one’s view of the game.
One potential distortion relates to how we understand each player’s contribution to a team’s performance. In fantasy football, a top-tier running back (RB) is way more valuable than a top-tier quarterback (QB).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passing the (climbing) grade</title>
      <link>/2019/05/27/passing-the-climbing-grade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/27/passing-the-climbing-grade/</guid>
      <description>This past weekend, I had the chance to climb at the New River Gorge, one of the best climbing destinations on the East coast (and probably the closest world-class crag to where I live). Unfortunately, I’m rehabbing a wrist injury, so the hardest climb I got on was graded 5.9, several notches below the level I’m trying to climb at consistently. Fortunately, it was the classic epic 80-foot Flight of the Gumby.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fantasy Football season in review (2017-2018)</title>
      <link>/2017/12/10/fantasy-football-season-in-review-2017-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/12/10/fantasy-football-season-in-review-2017-2018/</guid>
      <description>This season, a friend invited me to join his family’s Fantasy Football league, which gave me a chance to dabble in analytics. Prior to this season, I’ve been more interested in American Football the band than the sport.
I know people who make fantasy football decisions for non-rational reasons (e.g. choosing players out of loyalty). On the other hand, I also know those who use their intimate knowledge of the sport to take into account relevant information a novice like me might overlook (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>